Before they were soldiers, they were family. Before they were legends, they were
heroes. Before there was a nation, there was a fight for freedom.
The Patriot is a drama, history, war film directed by Roland Emmerich.
After proving himself on the field of battle in the French and Indian War, Benjamin Martin
wants nothing more to do with such things, preferring the simple life of a farmer.
But when his son Gabriel enlists in the army to defend their new nation, America, against
the British, Benjamin reluctantly returns to his old life to protect his son.
Benjamin Martin, played by Mel Gibson.
Gabriel Martin, played by Heath Ledger.
Charlotte Selton, played by Joely Richardson.
Col. William Tavington, played by Jason Isaacs.
Col. Harry Burwell, played by Chris Cooper.
Jean Villeneuve, played by Tchéky Karyo.
The Patriot is a 2000 American epic historical war film directed
by Roland Emmerich and written by Robert Rodat.
The film stars Mel Gibson, Heath Ledger, Joely Richardson,
Jason Isaacs, Chris Cooper, and Tom Wilkinson.
Set in Berkeley County, South Carolina, it follows Benjamin Martin (Gibson), an American colonist who is opposed to going to war with Great Britain but, along with his son
Gabriel (Ledger), gets swept into the American Revolutionary War when his home life is disrupted, and one of his sons is murdered by a cruel British officer (Isaacs).
The film had its world premiere in Century City on June 27, 2000, and was theatrically
released in the United States on June 30, 2000 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It received mixed-to-positive reviews from critics and grossed $215.3 million against a $110 million budget, and
was nominated for three Academy Awards including Best Cinematography and Best Original Score.
The Patriot generated significant controversy due its historical inaccuracies, in
particular its fictionalized portrayal of British figures and atrocities.
The portrayal of the protagonist, a composite character based on several persons including Francis
Marion; was also criticized for whitewashing the real figures' own wartime conduct.
The film explores themes of daughter, mission,
general, southern usa, loss of loved one.
The tone is emotional.